Someone on Earth had a sudden thought.
Kogoś na Ziemi naszła pewna myśl.
AUTHOR: HITOSHI IWAAKI (PUBLISHER: KODANSHA "AFTERNOON")
AUTOR: HITOSHI IWAAKI
METAMORPHOSIS
METAMORFOZA
How unfortunate.
Jaka szkoda.
I failed.
Nie udało mi się.
What's unfortunate?
Co się nie udało?
Shut up!
Zamknij się!
I guess I was dreaming.
Coś mi się śniło.
I feel like I didn't sleep too well.
Kiepsko dzisiaj spałem.
Did you find the "snake"?
Znalazłeś węża?
It feels kind of numb.
Ręka mi zdrętwiała.
Because you tied your earphone cord around it while half-asleep.
Bo przez sen owinąłeś ją kablem od słuchawek.
Sorry. I'll just have some toast.
Przepraszam. Zjem grzankę.
No, you need to have a proper breakfast.
Musisz zjeść porządne śniadanie.
I was really shook up last night.
Miałem ciężką noc.
That's my line.
To mój tekst.
Hot!
Gorąca!
It's just a spider.
To tylko pająk.
When are you going to get over that fear of bugs, Shinichi?
Kiedy przestaniesz bać się robaków, Shinichi?
The Japanese government
Rząd Japonii zaproponował trzy reformy.
-the ongoing global economic crisis… -The Japanese government has proposed…
- Chce walczyć z kryzysem gospodarczym… - Rząd Japonii zaproponował…
-Dad? Where's Mom? I'm hungry. -…at the OECD Ministerial Council Meeting.
Tato, gdzie mama? Jestem głodna.
It is expected to take some time before a resolution is reached.
Dojście do porozumienia trochę zajmie.
Next up in the news…
Kolejne wiadomości…
-Gotcha! -Huh?
Mam cię!
Murano?
Murano?
That was so fake.
Nie udawaj.
What was?
Czego?
You knew I was coming up behind you, didn't you?
Wiedziałeś, że za tobą idę, prawda?
No. No way!
Nie!
This is just a misunderstanding!
To jakieś nieporozumienie!
I mean…
To znaczy…
You idiot!
Ty idioto!
Why did you do that?
Dlaczego to zrobiłeś?
Tachikawa.
Tachikawa.
I have no idea.
Nie wiem.
I really don't.
Naprawdę nie wiem.
Is something wrong with your right hand?
Coś ci się stało w rękę?
Oh. No.
Nie.
It's nothing.
To nic takiego.
A snake!
Wąż!
It burrowed into my hand?
Mam go w ręce?
It's climbing up my arm?
Porusza się?
What's wrong, Shinichi?
Co się dzieje, Shinichi?
Help!
Pomocy!
What are you doing?
Co robisz?
Why did you tie up your arm?
Dlaczego związałeś sobie rękę?
A snake! A snake's in my arm!
Bo jest w niej wąż!
What?
Co?
A snake?
Wąż?
Wow.
Rety.
You take being half-asleep to a new level.
To jakiś nowy rodzaj lunatykowania?
I'm serious!
Mówię poważnie! Zrobił mi dziurę w ręce i do niej wszedł!
Yeah?
Tak? To gdzie ta dziura?
Look! It's right--
Patrz. Jest tutaj…
Shinichi, you'd better not be on drugs.
Shinichi, obyś nie brał narkotyków.
Of course I'm not!
Nie biorę!
Oh, really now, dear.
Ojejku, skarbie.
Weird.
To dziwne.
It doesn't hurt or anything.
Już mnie nie boli.
I wonder if that weird creature is actually inside my hand.
Czy to dziwne stworzenie jest w mojej ręce?
Izumi-kun!
Izumi-kun!
Playing games during class?
Grasz w gry na lekcji?
Whatever you were up to,
Nie wiem, co kombinowałeś, ale w klasie nie wolno używać telefonów.
But I had it turned off and…
- Wyłączyłem go, ale… - Słucham?
Sorry.
Przepraszam.
Oh, Murano. About this morning.
Murano, co do tego zajścia rano…
Man, she's pretty mad.
Jest bardzo zła.
Okay, fine.
Dobra.
Out of kindness to an old friend,
Przyjaźnimy się od wielu lat, więc ją za ciebie przeproszę.
Really? Thanks a lot.
Naprawdę? Dziękuję.
But what about you? Are you okay?
A ty jak się czujesz?
You've been acting strange all day.
Dziwnie się zachowujesz.
Yeah.
Tak.
I feel a little off.
Źle się czuję.
I'll talk to the teacher and ask to go home early.
Zapytam, czy mogę wyjść wcześniej.
I wonder if it's possible for your hand to move on its own.
Ciekawe, czy ręka może się sama ruszać.
But if this has anything to do with that weird creature I saw last night.
Ma to coś wspólnego z tym stworzeniem, które widziałem?
Misaki!
Misaki!
Misaki.
Misaki.
Thank goodness.
Dzięki Bogu.
DATING 12 WOMEN! POPULAR ATHLETE IN SHOCKING SEX SCANDAL!
ROMANS Z 12 KOBIETAMI! SPORTOWIEC UWIKŁANY W SKANDAL
Shinichi?
Shinichi?
He's home early.
Wcześnie wrócił.
Are you even my own right hand?
Jesteś moją ręką?
I'm going to test you.
Sprawdzę to.
You'd better not dodge.
Lepiej nie uciekaj.
How unfortunate.
Jaka szkoda.
I right hand fail.
Prawa ręka zawiodła.
Fail?
Zawiodła?
What about my right hand?
Co z moją prawą ręką?
I ate it.
Zjadłem ją.
Not talk good yet.
Nie umiem jeszcze dobrze mówić.
Teach me, Shinichi.
Naucz mnie, Shinichi.
What are you?
Czym ty jesteś?
Tired.
Zmęczony.
-Sleep. -Huh?
Spać.
Hang on a second!
Poczekaj.
I have tons of questions I want to ask you! Hey!
Mam do ciebie mnóstwo pytań!
Hey, come on!
Hej! Pokaż się!
Shinichi? Is something wrong?
Shinichi? Wszystko w porządku?
Shinichi, did you hear me?
Słyszysz mnie?
Don't come in!
Nie wchodź tu!
Nothing's wrong.
Wszystko w porządku.
TALKING RIGHT HAND
GADAJĄCA RĘKA
TALKING RIGHT HAND WEIRD SNAKE
GADAJĄCA RĘKA DZIWNY WĄŻ
BURROW INTO HUMAN
ŻYJĄCY W CZŁOWIEKU
There's nothing that seems relevant.
Nie ma żadnych informacji.
So I guess no one else has had this problem.
Chyba tylko ja mam taki problem.
Shinichi, dinner's ready!
Shinichi, kolacja!
I got a call from the school.
Dzwonili do mnie ze szkoły.
They said you left early.
Podobno wcześniej wyszedłeś.
Did something happen?
Coś się stało?
Not really.
Nie.
I just didn't feel well.
Tylko źle się czułem.
-Are you okay? -Yeah.
- Już ci lepiej? - Tak.
Oh, you're having seconds?
Chcesz dokładkę?
That's unusual.
A to nowość.
So you don't feel well, but you do have an appetite?
Źle się czujesz, ale masz apetyt?
I feel better now.
Teraz czuję się lepiej.
Does it matter?
Czy to ważne?
I can't tell Mom or Dad about my right hand.
Nie mogę powiedzieć rodzicom o ręce.
I love you, love you, love you lots!
Kocham cię, bardzo cię kocham!
Wall slam!
Ściana!
Oops. I had a bit too much.
Kurczę, za dużo wypiłem.
Drank too much.
Za dużo wypiłem.
Nakamura-san, your laundry.
Nakamura-san, pana pranie.
No. I can't tell anyone about this.
Nie. Nikomu nie mogę o tym powiedzieć.
Even if I went to the cops, they'd just think I'm crazy.
Nawet jeśli pójdę na policję, powiedzą, że oszalałem.
If they ran tests at a hospital,
Jeśli zrobią mi badania w szpitalu,
there would be a huge uproar.
wybuchnie afera.
What should I do?
Co mam zrobić?
Hey, wake up already.
Hej, obudź się.
It's morning?
Już rano?
It's morning.
Już rano.
It's finally morning and still…
Jest już rano, a on nadal…
I'm stuck in a nightmare.
Moje życie to koszmar.
What are you doing?
Co robisz?
Just what it looks like.
A jak myślisz?
I'm studying.
Uczę się.
Oh, you can talk normally now?
Teraz już płynnie mówisz?
So what are you, anyway?
Czym jesteś?
Don't tell me you're an alien?
Chyba nie kosmitą?
"Alien"?
„Kosmitą”?
What's that?
A co to jest?
That snake-like thing is what you really look like, right?
Naprawdę wyglądasz jak wąż?
I won't deny that none of the biology books I checked had anything about me.
W książkach do biologii nic o mnie nie napisano.
I don't know where I came from.
Nie wiem, skąd jestem.
The earliest memory I have
Pamiętam tylko,
is the sense of how unfortunate it was that I couldn't take the brain.
że byłem smutny, bo nie udało mi się przejąć mózgu.
"The brain"?
„Mózgu”?
You don't mean…
Chyba nie…
Are you going after my brain next?
Chcesz przejąć mój mózg?
If that were possible, I would have done so already.
Gdybym mógł, już bym to zrobił.
But it's not.
Ale nie mogę.
It's too late now that I've matured without having eaten your brain.
Już za późno.
It's quite unfortunate.
Jaka szkoda.
What would've happened if you'd succeeded in taking my brain?
A co by się stało, gdyby ci się udało?
You probably would have become
Pewnie stałbyś się
Gross.
To straszne.
Why me, anyway?
Dlaczego ja?
Coincidence.
Przez przypadek.
I didn't choose you specifically.
Nie wybrałem cię.
I guess I have to go to a hospital now, uproar or not.
Chyba muszę jechać do szpitala. Niech wybuchnie afera.
Why would you do that?
Po co tam jechać?
To have them cut you off.
Żeby cię odcięli.
That would be undesirable.
Nie chcemy tego.
I feed on the nutrients carried by your bloodstream to survive.
Żywię się składnikami odżywczymi z twojego krwiobiegu.
So, if I were to be cut off,
Jeśli mnie odetną,
I would shrivel up and die.
zwiędnę i umrę.
Plus, you would lose your right hand.
A ty stracisz rękę.
It'd be a loss for both of us.
Obaj ucierpimy.
"Both of us"?
„Obaj”? To ty zjadłeś moją rękę bez pozwolenia!
How about this?
Może zrobimy tak?
I'll fine-tune the circuitry so that while I'm asleep,
Dostroję obwody, więc gdy będę spać,
you can control the hand just like before.
będziesz mógł używać ręki jak wcześniej.
What?
Co?
That's sufficient, no?
Pasuje ci to?
Moving forward, we should cooperate and coexist.
Będziemy współpracować i koegzystować.
That is our only option.
To nasze jedyne wyjście.
What?
Co?
Who said you get to decide?
Dlaczego ty masz decydować?
I'm tired, so I'm going to sleep.
Jestem zmęczony, idę spać.
Wait a minute!
Czekaj!
You always do that when things get inconvenient for you!
Zawsze tak robisz, gdy jest problem!
Use me with care.
Uważaj na mnie.
Where's my bacon and eggs?
A moje jajka i bekon?
You said you didn't want any yesterday.
Wczoraj nie chciałeś.
You said I should have a proper breakfast, right?
Mówiłaś, że mam jeść porządne śniadanie.
Can I have more toast, too?
Mogę dokładkę grzanek?
You're so fickle.
Aleś ty kapryśny.
Violent incidents are happening all over the nation.
W całym kraju dochodzi do brutalnych napaści.
Another murder?
Kolejne morderstwo?
Yeah.
Tak.
A mother and her daughter were killed.
Zginęły matka i córka.
Not only were their bodies in terrible shape,
Ich ciała były zmasakrowane.
but it also seems the father is the killer and now he's missing.
Podejrzewają ojca, który zaginął.
There was also a dismembering in Osaka
W Osace znaleziono poćwiartowane ciało, a w Miyagi ciało wisiało jak pranie.
Not when we're eating, dear.
Nie przy jedzeniu, kochanie.
Oops, sorry.
Przepraszam.
Hey, Shinichi, look.
Shinichi, patrz.
You're fine with them now?
Już się ich nie boisz?
Fine with what?
Czego?
But you and bugs…
Tych robaków.
This is a different route from yesterday.
Idziemy inną drogą niż wczoraj.
You're awake?
Nie śpisz?
Where are you going?
Dokąd idziesz?
I decided to talk to the police.
Porozmawiam z policją.
Don't do that.
Nie rób tego.
You'll be isolated and turned into an experimental subject or a sample.
Zamkną cię i zrobią z ciebie obiekt badań.
Either way, you won't be able to lead a normal life anymore.
Nie będziesz mógł normalnie żyć.
What should I do, then?
To co mam zrobić?
I already told you this morning.
Mówiłem ci rano.
To cooperate and coexist is our only…
Współpraca i koegzystencja…
Stop!
Stój!
Not so loud!
Ciszej!
One of mine is close.
- Zbliża się mój gatunek. - Co?
"One of mine" as in another of my species.
Idzie ktoś z mojego gatunku.
What did you say?
Co takiego?
Wait. How can you tell?
Chwila. Skąd wiesz?
I can sense something like brain waves.
Potrafię wyczuć fale mózgowe.
It's my first time sensing it, but I can tell it's one of mine.
Pierwszy raz je czuję, ale wiem, że to ktoś z moich.
It's about 200 meters straight that way.
Jest 200 metrów w tamtą stronę.
There are other people who went through the same thing as me?
Nie tylko mnie to spotkało?
Right.
W prawo.
Go right.
Idź w prawo.
Shinichi?
Shinichi?
Okay.
Idę.
Turn left up ahead.
Skręć w lewo.
It seems the other has sensed me, too.
On też mnie wyczuł.
What's wrong?
Co jest?
Go.
Idź.
You said it's one of you.
To ktoś z twoich.
Could it be a person who's had his brain taken over?
To osoba, której przejęto mózg?
Possibly.
Pewnie tak.
No way.
Nie ma mowy.
That's creepy as hell.
To straszne.
I need to know what exactly I am.
Muszę się dowiedzieć, czym dokładnie jestem.
That information should be valuable to you, as well.
Ta informacja tobie też się przyda.
Fine.
Dobrze.
Twenty meters more.
Jeszcze 20 metrów.
It's around that corner.
Za rogiem.
-It seems to be eating. -What?
- Chyba coś je. - Co robi?
A dog's eating another dog?
Pies zjada psa?
You also failed?
Tobie też się nie udało?
Please stop talking.
Przestań mówić, proszę.
You with your location in your host.
Ty zamieszkałeś w człowieku.
Me with my animal host.
Ja w zwierzęciu.
Both dissatisfied.
Obaj jesteśmy niezadowoleni.
-Run! -What?
- Uciekaj! - Co?
Run! Hurry!
Biegnij! Szybko!
What the hell? You told me to go there and now you tell me to run?
Kazałeś mi tam iść, a teraz każesz mi uciekać?
I sensed that it wants to kill you!
On chce cię zabić!
It harbors an intense suspicion toward you because you are still human.
Jest wobec ciebie podejrzliwy, bo nadal jesteś człowiekiem.
It intends to fight.
Chce walczyć.
We'll fight here.
- Będziemy walczyć tutaj. - Co? Walczyć?
If it kills you, I'll die, too.
Jeśli cię zabije, ja też umrę.
Here it comes.
Jest.
What the…
Co do…
You've got to be kidding me!
Chyba sobie żartujesz!
That's way out of line!
To już przesada!
Is that its heart?
To jego serce?
Look.
Patrz.
It's about to die.
Zaraz umrze.
It was living off the dog's organs and digestive system, as I'd suspected.
Narządy i układ pokarmowy psa utrzymywały go przy życiu.
I had no idea there were more of you.
Nie wiedziałem, że jest was więcej.
Its core was only the head.
Jego rdzeniem była głowa.
It controls the rest of the body by seizing control of the nervous system,
Przejął kontrolę nad ciałem przez układ nerwowy,
but because the core itself morphed into wings,
ale tylko rdzeń zmienił się w skrzydła,
its focus was dispersed, creating a gap in its defenses.
więc był rozproszony i nie mógł się bronić.
And you'd finally found one of your own kind.
W końcu znalazłeś kogoś ze swojego gatunku.
A dog, huh?
Pies?
I suppose it's partially due to its maturation environment,
Dojrzewał w takim środowisku i nie przyłożył się do nauki.
That's why I was victorious.
Dlatego wygrałem.
It's like I'm talking with an insect
Jakbym rozmawiał z robakiem,
that doesn't have a shred of empathy.
który nie ma w sobie empatii.
Shinichi, it's cold.
Shinichi, zimna.
2 DAYS AGO
2 DNI WCZEŚNIEJ
Someone on Earth had a sudden thought.
Kogoś na Ziemi naszła pewna myśl.
"Life must be protected."
„Trzeba chronić życie”.
Next time, "Demon in the Flesh."
Następny odcinek: „Demon w ciele”.